JITENDRA SONI Accountant with India 8 Years of Experience

D.O.B.: 16-Nov-1977 Nationality: India

Location: Hyderabad, India Mobile: +91 7416825383 Email: jkmost@gmail.com Indian Passport no: 2183339



PROFILE

JITENDRA SONI is an accomplished accountant with 6+ years of experience as a accountant. He has proven success in organizing tasks, smoothing accounting work from limited time period and resources is searching for a Oil & Gas , Real Estate, Construction or hospitality industry where my experience and skills would be put in use.

OBJECTIVE

Applying 6 years of Indian Accountant experience combined with proven expertise in managing a high-end trading and distributors company..

EDUCATION

SIKKIM MANIPAL UNIVERSITY , Raipur, Chhatisgar, India MBA – FINANCE – JUNE 2010

LANGUAGES

English — Excellent reading, writing and speaking **Hindi** — Excellent reading, writing and speaking **Gujarati** - Excellent reading and speaking

SPECIALIZED SKILLS

- Excellent interpersonal and communication skills
- Multi-tasking abilities with proficiency in organizing and managing different tasks
- Expert knowledge of generating Sales Invoice and online work process.
- Skilled in book keeping and BRS and financial records
- Thorough insights in stock inventory maintaining branch wise.
- Proficient in timely making payment to suppliers by RTGS or writing cheques.
- GST knowledge and tax related matter.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

A.H COMMERCIAL, Raipur (C.G.)

Agst 2007- Dec. 2010

Asst.Accountant

- Individually handing of books of accounts up to income & expenditure statement balance sheet in coordination with external and statutory audits.
- Provide MIS Report.
- Handling petty cash.
- Payroll preparation on monthly basis.
- Proof read of financial reports created by finance manager.
- Support and assist tax consultant.
- Verification of a variety of financial records.
- Maintenance of TDS registers and issue certificate to parties

TRAININGS & PROGRAM

SAP FI/CO from Reliance Global Services

9 Months.

• General Ledger:

Creation of Company and Company Code.

Creation of Chart of accounts.

Gl posting(post with clearing, open item and account clearing and reversal of document

• Account Payable

Creation of Vendor master data and accounting view.

Configuration of settings for down payment and special GL transaction.

Creation of house banks and settings for reconciliation of bank accounts.

• Account Receivable

Creation of master data and accounting view.

Down payment and special GL transaction.

Configuration of setting for incoming payment, dunning procedure.

• Asset Account

Creation of Asset classes, asset masters-Main and Sub.

Line settlement of Asset under Construction, setting for depreciation run.

Controlling

Cost Element Accounting

Cost Center Accounting.

Internal Order.

Profit Center Accounting.

Product Costing.

• Integration

Integration of FI-MM and FI-SD modules.

Tulsiram Hanumanbagas Gilada

Oct 2011 to Sept 2017

(Importer & Distributor of Rubber Chemicals, Hyderabad)

DESIGNATION: Accountant **JOB PROFILE**:

- Prepare and maintain the books of accounts.
- Preparation and timely submission of statutory returns online.
- Preparation of reconciliation of Bank accounts, suppliers accounts, customers accounts etc.
- Maintain the stock items of all branches (Hyderabad, Chennai, Bangalore & Cochin).
- Ensure timely payment of all dues to suppliers and other service providers.
- Ensure the preparation and payment of staff salary before end of the month.
- Preparations and presentation of books of accounts to statutory auditors and ensure the timely completion of audit.

TESORO TRADELINKS [Nov 2017 to Present]

(Top Importer & Distributor of Art Paper in South India region)

- Prepare and maintain the books of accounts in Tally.
- Maintain the Stock items of all branches (Hyderabad, Kanpur)
- Raising Import Purchase Invoices & High Seas & Sales Invoices.
- BRS and Reconciliation of Debtors & Creditors Accounts.
- Maintain timely Petty Cash & all Journal exp entry.
- Ensure the preparation and payment of staff salary.
- Post and process journal entries to ensure all business transactions are recorded.
- Update accounts receivable and issue invoices.
- Update accounts payable and perform reconciliations.
- Assist in the processing of balance sheets, income statements and other financial statements according to legal and company accounting and financial guidelines.
- Assist with reviewing of expenses, payroll records etc. as assigned.
- Prepare and submit weekly/monthly Sales reports.
- Assist senior accountants in the preparation of monthly/yearly closings.
- Good knowledge in TDS, GST.

OTHER INTERESTS

Music Instruments, Indoor games, Cricket Playing, watching YouTube Innovative videos, Gadgets freak.

THANKS

JITENDRA SONI